Inderjeet Singh Khalsa (1) Featured

DevOps, Platform automation, CI/CD, Kubernetes, Docker, AWS, Powershell, Python, Batch , WSH VB script , Ansible-Tower, vRA , vRO , AWX, Configuration Mgmt, Build Mgmt, Change mgmt, Unix, SQL, Shell Scripting, plsql, GIT.



Current Designation: Associate Consultant Total Experience: 7 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: Northern Trust Operating Services Notice Period: 2 Months

Current Location: Pune Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Information Technology]

Pref. Location: Pune

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: sql,linux, jira, stash, bamboo, git, ansible, aws,docker,powershell,unix,sql,linux, shell scripting, plsql, shell

programming, jira, stash, bamboo, git, ansible, aws,docker,orchestration,powershell

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 10-Sep-20 Last Modified: 10-Sep-20

Summary

Platform automation & DevOps Engineer with over 7 years of versatile experience in Infrastructure automation, DevOps, Build & Release engineering, IT Monitoring, business and systems analysis, installation and configuration projects. Experience in directing projects from inception to execution including project team interaction, code packaging and successful deployment. Expert in managing technical support operations, diligently troubleshooting issues to identify root causes and prevent recurrence in PROD/UAT/QA environment

Work Experience

Northern Trust Operating Services as Associate Consultant Oct 2017 to Till Date

Role: Infrastructure Automation Engineer

- Defined and Implemented efficient end-to-end provisioning Automation solutions using vRealize Orchestrator & Automation
- Had been responsible for designing, creating, maintaining and continually improving orchestrated workflow to automate IT processes throughout the enterprise.
- Had developed projects for teams from Middleware, Database, UNIX and Windows engineering group using vRA/vRO & AWX Orchestrators.
- Collaborated with SME, analyst, designers and clients to develop automation solutions for providing self service capabilities for our clients to simplify IT.
- Leveraged Ansible tower & Ansible combination for projects with explicit requirement of provisioning and configuration on large number of UNIX machines (1000+ VMs), to automate repetitive tasks.
- Developed wrapper shell scripts for support team to monitor a Java based project also for build conduct and management support.
- Served as a SME for automation and orchestration. Also, supported the existing Automation Workflow, provisioning scripts
- Authored automated solutions in Powershell for several windows based machines.
- Also acquainted with batch and WSH vbscript for automation on windows machines.
- Developed several microservices for installation of software/tools post VM build in vRealize Orchestrator.
- Lead the team in documentation creation from nil to an extensive list of documents for various process carried out within the team
- Independently designed, developed and delivered SharePoint sites and Web Part Forms

Accenture as Senior Software Engineer

May 2013 to Oct 2017

1. Accenture - SEZ Park, Hinjewadi Phase-1, Pune Jan 2017- Present

Senior Software Engineer

Project: Cox

Client: Cox communications

Deployment & Configuration Management

Handling Ansible Playbooks. Maintaining configuration information for various Cox systems.

Creating Ansible-playbooks for additional functionality coming up in system.

Deploying of packages in DEV/QA environment.

Debugging/ troubleshooting the errors while deployment of packages.

Using GIT to add-commit-merge the changes in various Ansible and code Repos.

Using Gradle to build the packages out of code.

Shell scripting to automate the Configuration changes.

Atlassian Tool

Administrating various Atlassian tools like Jira, Bamboo, Stash, Confluence, Crowd.

Maintain users, groups, scheme, roles, Permission in Jira tool.

Maintain Repos in Stash and creation of packages through Bamboo tool.

Creation/Updating/Deletion of users through Crowd.

Bamboo plan creation and automating deployment in Ansible server.

2. Accenture - Infinity Park, Malad (East) Mumbai May 2013- Dec 2016

Software Engineer Project: Atlas Run Client: BNP Paribas

Project Planning

Managing requirement gathering, system analysis and finalising of technical/functional specifications.

Managing Unix Environment allocation for APAC (Asia - Pacific) region after understanding the activities needed for the project.

After allocation making the allocated environment as per production, this may involve Component refresh, Mount creation,

File system creation, space management, Database creation, Data restoration etc.

Cooperating & communicating with other team members for efficient work.

Managing smooth implementation and testing of project at client location.

Providing implementation as well as implementation support to production team.

Creation of documents useful for Project deployment in production like release document, rollback plan and implementation plan.

Maintaining good relation with end Users.

Technical

Running and scheduling batches (EOD, EOM, supplementary, unloading and loading in DEV/UAT testing.

Analysing aborts and errors during the batch run hence advising project team with possible root cause.

Refreshing BO reports from the loaded database

Created shell scripts to minimize manual task or operations.

Successfully Deployed many Financial/Non Financial projects like FATCA.

Helping Production teams with code deployment, and supporting for possible issue during first project live run.

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Information Technology) from institute of engineering and technology (davv) indore in 2013

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
MYSQL, ORACLE(SQL) / PL-SQL		2016	3 Year(s) 9 Month(s)
Windows XP/ 7 / DOS / Unix / Linux.		2020	6 Year(s) 1 Month(s)
Jira, Stash, Bamboo, Crucible, Crowd		2017	0 Year(s) 7 Month(s)

1/22/2021 https://freesearch.naukri.com/preview/printResume?uname=1bf5dc426b5e5ab8655f0bb7b9aa5d300b5508071b140f430043480a59...

Python	2020	2 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
VRO/VRA	2020	2 Year(s) 6 Month(s)
POWERSHELL	2017	2 Year(s) 5 Month(s)
Kubernetes	2020	0 Year(s) 6 Month(s)
DOCKER	2020	1 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
Shell Scripting	2020	6 Year(s) 6 Month(s)
Ansible	2020	2 Year(s) 7 Month(s)

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Proficient			
Hindi	Proficient			
Punjabi	Proficient			

Projects

Project Title: Infrastructure Automation Engineer Client: Northern Trust Operating Services

Nature of Employment: Full Time

Duration: Oct 2017 - Till Date
Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Details: Defined and Implemented efficient end-to-end provisioning Automation solutions using vRealize Orchestrator & Automation.

Had been responsible for designing, creating, maintaining and continually improving orchestrated workflow to automate IT processes throughout the enterprise.

Had developed projects for teams from Middleware, Database, UNIX and Windows engineering group using vRA/vRO & AWX Orchestrators.

Collaborated with SME, analyst, designers and clients to develop automation solutions for providing self service capabilities for our clients to simplify IT.

Leveraged Ansible tower & Ansible combination for projects with explicit requirement of provisioning and configuration on large number of UNIX machines (1000+ VMs), to automate repetitive tasks.

Developed wrapper shell scripts for support team to monitor a Java based project also for build conduct and management

Served as a SME for automation and orchestration. Also, supported the existing Automation W

Project Title: Cox Pune
Client: cox communications

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Jan 2017 - May 2017
Project Location: Pune Duration: Jan 2017 - May 2017
Onsite / Offsite

Role: Other Team Size: 6

Skill Used: GIT as Version control Ansible as deployment automation Gradle as a build tool Atlassian tools - Jira, Stash,

Bamboo, Confluence etc... Role Description: DEV-OPS

Project Details: The Cox project comes under Client Managment project. I am working as a part of Devops team, responsible for many tasks like Deploying code using Ansible, controlling code version using git and being as a administrator to atlassian tools

We are responsible to provide configuration along with deployment of code in Dev and Qa

Project Title: Atlas Run

Client: BNPP

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Sep 2013 - Dec 2016

Project Location: Infinity park, Accenture malad east, Mumbai Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Role: Other Team Size: 12

Skill Used: Unix,SQL,c++, Java, Unix Shell Scripting,

Role Description: I am designated as delivery engineer. What ever components were developed were tested by us. We created technical document if the project was supposed to go in production. Had successfully deployed projects in production(like Fatca)

Project Details: Project involved Atlas tool where EOD, EOM, supplementary were run. After Atlas part info-center loading is done. It involved error debugging and error solving on Atlas part. Atlas part involves cobol components while Info-center involves database(SQL level) issues.

Affirmative Action

Category: General

Physically Challenged: No

Work Authorization

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time